Guide to the Leonard S. Marcus Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Leonard S. Marcus papers
1850-2015
1975-2015
GEN MSS 1489
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
113.75
(102 boxes)
The collection documents the work of Leonard S. Marcus, including the research, writing, and publication of books, articles, and other short works; work as contributing editor and children's literature reviewer at Parenting magazine; the curation of exhibitions at the New York Public Library and Eric Carle Museum for Picture Book Art; and trusteeship of the Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art. The collection also contains Marcus's personal and professional correspondence and small amounts of photographs, publishing promotional materials, historic book and toy catalogs, posters, and other printed ephemera. Includes audio recordings and notes from Marcus's interviews with prominent children's literature authors, illustrators, and publishers, including Maurice Sendak, Judy Blume, and Madeleine L'Engle.
Marcus, Leonard S., 1950-
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Boxes 70-90 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Boxes 69, 91 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Cumberland Rare Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2015; and gift of Leonard S. Marcus (Yale 1972), 2016.
Arrangement
Arranged into two groupings: September 2015 Acquisition and August 2016 Acquisition.
Leonard S. Marcus (1950- )
Leonard S. Marcus (1950- ) (Yale 1972) is an American critic and scholar of children's literature. Marcus received a bachelor's degree in history from Yale University in 1972, a master's degree in fine arts from the University of Iowa Graduate Writers Workshop in Poetry in 1974, and an honorary doctorate of human letters from Bank Street College of Education in 2007.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the work of Leonard S. Marcus, including the research, writing, and publication of books, articles, and other short works; work as contributing editor and children's literature reviewer at Parenting magazine; the curation of exhibitions at the New York Public Library and Eric Carle Museum for Picture Book Art; and trusteeship of the Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art. The collection also contains Marcus's personal and professional correspondence and small amounts of photographs, publishing promotional materials, historic book and toy catalogs, posters, and other printed ephemera. Includes audio recordings and notes from Marcus's interviews with prominent children's literature authors, illustrators, and publishers, including Maurice Sendak, Judy Blume, and Madeleine L'Engle.
A significant portion of the papers documents Marcus's research, writing, and publication of Margaret Wise Brown: Awakened by the Moon (Morrow, 1992), a biography of Goodnight Moon author Margaret Wise Brown. Includes papers pertaining to Marcus's other books, including Dear Genius: The Letters of Ursula Nordstrom (HarperCollins, 1998); Author Talk (Simon & Schuster, 2000); Storied City: A Children's Book-Walking Tour Guide to New York City (Dutton, 2003); The Wand in the Word: Conversations with Writers of Fantasy (Candlewick, 2006); Minders of Make-Believe: Idealists, Entrepreneurs, and the Shaping of American Children's Literature (Houghton Mifflin, 2008); Funny Business: Conversations with Writers of Comedy (Candlewick, 2009); Listening for Madeleine: A Portrait of Madeleine L'Engle in Many Voices (Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 2012); and Show Me A Story! Why Picture Books Matter (Candlewick, 2012).
The collection also includes papers concerning Marcus's shorter works, including articles, reviews, forewords, and talks. Also present are papers concerning Marcus's work with museums and exhibitions, including The Picture Book Made New: Margaret Wise Brown and Her Illustrators at the Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art (2005) and The ABC of It: Why Children's Books Matter at the New York Public Library (2013-2014). Clippings, photographs, audiovisual materials, and electronic media related to Marcus's life and work are present throughout.
Children's literature, American -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Illustrators -- United States; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Brown, Margaret Wise, 1910-1952; L'Engle, Madeleine; Nordstrom, Ursula; Sendak, Maurice; Marcus, Leonard S., 1950-
- September 2015 Acquisition, circa 1850-2015; circa 1975-2015; 110.08; (98 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Cumberland Rare Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2015.
  Arrangement
  Organized into four series: I. Writings, circa 1981-2015. II. Exhibitions and Museum Work, circa 1985-2013. III. Correspondence, circa 1979-2013. IV. Publishing Promotional Materials and Printed Ephemera, circa 1850-2015.
  - Writings, circa 1981-2015; 77.5; (68 boxes)
    Scope and Contents
    Documents the research, writing, and publication of Marcus's works, including books, articles, reviews, forewords, and talks. Includes research materials, notes, drafts, correspondence, publicity, and clippings. Note that a significant portion of Marcus's research materials consists of duplicates of archival materials held by other libraries. Where possible, the institution holding the originals has been noted. Inquiries about originals of these materials should be directed to the holding institution.
    Organized into two subseries: Books and Short Works.
    - Books, circa 1983-2013
      Documents the research, writing, and publication of Marcus's books. Includes research materials, notes, drafts, correspondence, publicity, and clippings. Significant materials concerning Margaret Wise Brown: Awakened by the Moon (Morrow, 1992); Dear Genius: The Letters of Ursula Nordstrom (HarperCollins, 1998); Listening for Madeleine: A Portrait of Madeleine L'Engle in Many Voices (Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 2012); and Minders of Make-Believe: Idealists, Entrepreneurs, and the Shaping of American Children's Literature (Houghton Mifflin, 2008). Note that a significant portion of Marcus's research materials consists of duplicates of archival materials held by other libraries. Where possible, the institution holding the originals has been noted. Inquiries about originals of these materials should be directed to the holding institution.
      Arranged alphabetically by title.
      - 75 Years of Children's Book Week Posters: Celebrating Great Illustrators of American Children's Books, circa 1992-1994
        - Japanese edition, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Children's Book Council poster book introduction, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Poster book captions, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Poster book captions master copy, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
        - Poster book correspondence, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Children's Book Council features article, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Introduction and acknowledgments, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Children's Book Council slides, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Poster book expense receipts, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Book Week captions, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Poster book, Knopf, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Wolfsonian Research Center, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - de Grummond collection, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Research material, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Introduction (copy edited), circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Press release, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Poster book publicity and reviews, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
        - Caption revisions, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Research leads, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Morrow history (copy edited), circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Knopf catalog, circa 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - The Annotated Phantom Tollbooth, circa 2010-2011
        - Jules Feiffer, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Jules Feiffer introduction, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Norton Juster's new notes on The Phantom Tollbooth, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Annotated copy of The Phantom Tollbooth, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Annotated Phantom Tollbooth manuscript, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
        - Norton Juster interview, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Revised introduction, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - Research material, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Norrton Juster comedy interview, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Annotated Phantom Tollbooth trip to Indianapolis, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - Research materials and notes, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Second pass master copy, circa 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 36-38)
        - Second pass master copy, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1824-1826)
        - Annotated Phantom Tollbooth illustrations, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1827-1828)
        - Annotated Phantom Tollbooth text, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1829)
        - Annotated Phantom Tollbooth reviews, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1830-1831)
        - Research materials, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1832)
        - Correspondence and research materials, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1833)
        - Meetings and notes, circa 2010-2011 (Box 68, Folder 1834)
        - Color layout fourth pass, 2011-05-13 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2307-2308)
      - Author Talk, circa 1999-2011
        General
        Originally published as Talking with Authors.
        - Author Talk letters, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 39)
        - School Library Journal excerpt from Author Talk, circa 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        - Author Talk manuscript, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        - Author Talk readers, circa 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 42)
        - Bruce Brooks, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 43)
        - Author Talk readers, circa 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 44)
        - eToys, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        - Author Talk publicity, circa 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
        - Interview with Bruce Brooks, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 49)
        - Talking with Authors, Simon & Schuster, circa 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
        - Karen Cushman, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 51-52)
        - Russell Freedman, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 53)
        - Lee Bennett Hopkins interview, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 54)
        - James Howe, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 55)
        - Johanna Hurwitz, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 56)
        - E. L. Konigsburg, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 57)
        - Lois Lowry, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 58)
        - Ann M. Martin, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 59)
        - Nicholasa Mohr, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 60)
        - Gary Paulsen, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 61)
        - Jon Scieszka, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 62-63)
        - Seymour Simon, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 64)
        - Laurence Yep, circa 1999-2011 (Box 3, Folder 65)
        - Developmental Studies Center reprint from Author Talk, circa 2000-2011 (Box 18, Folder 446)
        - Longman Author Talk excerpt, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 447)
        - Pearson Author Talk reprint, circa 2000-2011 (Box 18, Folder 448)
      - A Caldecott Celebration: Seven Artists and Their Paths to the Caldecott Medal, circa 1997-2007
        Originally published as A Caldecott Celebration: Six Artists Share Their Paths to the Caldecott Medal.
        - William Steig, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 66)
        - Chris Van Allsburg, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 67)
        - Marcia Brown, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
        - Maurice Sendak, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 70-70a)
        - David Wiesner, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 71)
        - William Steig letters from Kerlan collection, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 72-73)
        - A Caldecott Celebration reviews, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 74)
        - A Caldecott Celebration final draft, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 75)
        - A Caldecott Celebration introduction, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 76)
        - Walker Books project, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 77)
        - Robert McCloskey, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 78)
        - A Caldecott Celebration letters from readers, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 79)
        - A Caldecott Celebration correspondence, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 80)
        - A Caldecott Celebration proofs, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 81)
        - A Caldecott Celebration miscellaneous thoughts, notes, and things to do, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 82)
        - A Caldecott Celebration captions and glossary, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 83)
        - A Caldecott Celebration permissions file, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 84)
        - A Caldecott Celebration publicity, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 85)
        - HarperCollins revisions, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 86)
        - Research and notes, circa 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 87)
        - A Caldecott Celebration 10th anniversary edition, 2007 (Box 62, Folder 1668-1669)
        - A Caldecott Celebration proof, circa 2007 (Box 97 (Oversize), Folder 2319)
      - Dear Genius: The Letters of Ursula Nordstrom, circa 1995-2000
        - Angel, Marie, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 88)
        - Armstrong, William, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 89)
        - Asch, Frank, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 90)
        - Averill, Esther, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 91)
        - Baker, Betty, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 92)
        - Benchley, Nathaniel, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 93)
        - Blegvad, Erik, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 94)
        - Borack, Barbara, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 95)
        - Brown, Margaret Wise, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 96-99)
        - Bonsall, Crosby, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 100)
        - Burkert, Nancy Ekholm, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 101)
        - Calhoun, Mary, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 102)
        - Carlson, Natalie Savage, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 103)
        - Chalmers, Mary, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 104)
        - Dahl, Roald, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 105)
        - Dana, Barbara, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 106)
        - DeJong, Meindert, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 107-113)
        - Deutsch, Babette, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 114)
        - Donovan, John, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 115)
        - Edwards, Julie Andrews, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 116)
        - Ehrlich, Bettina, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 117)
        - Fitzhugh, Louise, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 118)
        - Frascino, Edward, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 119)
        - Floethe, Louise and Richard Floethe, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 120)
        - Gipson, Fred, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 121)
        - Gorey, Edward, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 122)
        - Graham, Margaret Bloy, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 123)
        - Gregory, Dick, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 124)
        - Haviland, Virginia, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 125)
        - Hentoff, Nat, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 126)
        - Hirschman, Susan, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 127)
        - Hoban, Lillian, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 128)
        - Hoban, Russell, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 129-130)
        - Hoff, Syd, circa 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 131-132)
        - Hirschman, Susan, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 133-134)
        - Hurd, Clement and Thacher Hurd, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 135-136)
        - Jewell, Nancy, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 137)
        - Jackson, Jesse, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 138)
        - Johnson, Crockett, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 139)
        - Johnson, Edgar and Annabel Johnson, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 140)
        - Johnson, Gerald, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 141)
        - Keats, Ezra Jack, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 142)
        - Keeshan, Robert, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 143)
        - Kellogg, Steven, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 144)
        - Kerr, M. E., circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 145)
        - Kessler, Leonard, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 146)
        - Knight, Hilary, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 147)
        - Kraus, Robert, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 148)
        - Krauss, Ruth, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 149-150)
        - Kunhardt, Dorothy, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 151)
        - Kuskin, Karla, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 152-153)
        - Langton, Jane, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 154)
        - Le Gallienne, Eva, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 155)
        - Lexau, Joan, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 156)
        - Lindquist, Jennie, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 157)
        - Lipsyte, Robert, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 158)
        - Lobel, Arnold and Anita Lobel, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 159)
        - Lord, Walter, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 160)
        - Lowrey, Janette, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 161)
        - Mammen, Edward, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 162)
        - Manushkin, Fran, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 163)
        - McClintock, Mike, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 164)
        - McCully, Emily, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 165)
        - Minarik, Else, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 166)
        - Monjo, F. N., circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 167)
        - Montresor, Beni, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 168)
        - Neville, Emily Cheney, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 169)
        - Newberry, Clare Turlay, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 170-171)
        - Nordstrom, Ursula, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 172-174)
        - O'Gorman, Ned, circa 1995-2000 (Box 6, Folder 175)
        - Pène du Bois, William, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 176)
        - Rey, H. A. and Margaret Rey, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 177)
        - Rodgers, Mary, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 178)
        - Russ, Lavinia, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 179)
        - Schlein, Miriam, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 180)
        - Selsam, Millicent, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 181)
        - Sendak, Maurice, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 182-183)
        - Shalit, Gene, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 184)
        - Shecter, Ben, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 185)
        - Sherman, Allan, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 186)
        - Shippen, Katherine, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 187)
        - Silverstein, Shel, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 188)
        - Simont, Marc, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 189)
        - Singer, Isaac B., circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 190)
        - Steptoe, John, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 191)
        - Stolz, Mary, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 192-194)
        - Sutherland, Zena, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 195)
        - Thompson, Kay, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 196)
        - Tippett, James, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 197)
        - Udry, Janice May, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 198)
        - Ungerer, Tomi, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 199)
        - White, E. B., circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 200-201)
        - Williams, Garth, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 202)
        - Wilder, Laura Ingalls, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 203)
        - Wojciechowska, Maia, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 204)
        - Woods, George, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 205)
        - Ylla, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 206)
        - Zolotow, Charlotte, circa 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 207)
        - Ursula Nordstrom new information and corrections, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 208-209)
        - Dear Genius illustrations, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 210)
        - Harper newsletter articles, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 211)
        - Ursula Nordstrom important leads, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 212)
        - Mary Griffith, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 213)
        - Ursula Nordstrom letters, disk and printed copy, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 214)
        - Ursula Nordstrom letters, interviews, leads, etc., circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 215)
        - Ursula Nordstrom introduction, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 216)
        - Articles by and about Ursula Nordstrom, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 217)
        - CCBC-Net Discussion of Dear Genius, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 218)
        - Dear Genius correspondence and master index of Harper warehouse files, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 219-220)
        - Dear Genius letters from readers, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 221-222)
        - Dear Genius reviews, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 223-224)
        - Ursula Nordstrom footnote material, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 225-226)
        - Dear Genius reviews, circa 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 227-228)
        - Dear Genius paperback edition, HarperCollins, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 229)
        - Publicity and promotion ideas, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 230-231)
        - Ursula Nordstrom, Columbia University, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 232)
        - Ursula Nordstrom, University of Oregon, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 233)
        - de Grummond Collection, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 234)
        - Nancy Crampton, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 235)
        - Ursula Nordstrom letters chosen so far, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 236)
        - Second batch of Ursula Nordstrom letters, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 237)
        - Ursula Nordstrom letters to consider adding, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 238)
        - Research and notes, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 239)
        - Ursula Nordstrom letters, circa 1995-2000 (Box 10, Folder 240-247)
        - Dear Genius manuscript, circa 1997 (Box 10, Folder 248-250)
        - Dear Genius index, circa 1997 (Box 10, Folder 251)
        - Dear Genius book tour, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 252)
      - An Épinal Album: Popular Prints from Nineteenth-century France, circa 1983-1984
        - Album book, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 431)
        - Album prints, circa 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 804-805)
      - Funny Business: Conversations with Writers of Comedy, circa 2007-2009
        Also known as its working title, Don't Make Me Laugh.
        - Funny Business talk notes, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 253)
        - Funny Business publicity, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 254)
        - Funny Business reviews, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 255)
        - Funny Business letters, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 256)
        - Illustrations, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 257)
        - Caption information, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 258)
        - Don't Make Me Laugh main file, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 259)
        - Don't Make Me Laugh headnotes, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 260)
        - Don't Make Me Laugh introduction, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 261)
        - Don't Make Me Laugh funny quotes, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 262)
        - Judy Blume, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 263)
        - Lauren Child, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 264)
        - Draft, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 265)
        - Beverly Cleary, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 266-268)
        - Sharon Creech, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 269)
        - Christopher Paul Curtis, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 270)
        - Anne Fine, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 271)
        - Anne Fine art, circa 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 272)